# J.D. Fillmore | Front-End Developer

jdfillmore.dev@gmail.com | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github

#### **CAREER PROFILE**

Front-End Developer with 8 years of experience designing and developing responsive websites & web applications for small to large companies. Most recent achievement: helping Battlefield Equipment Rentals by adding features to React, TypeScript & JavaScript machine rental web applications, resulting in millions in revenue and saving thousands of man hours during the COVID-19 pandemic.

#### **SKILLS**

Experience with: JavaScript Frameworks (React - React Hooks, React ContextAPI State Management, Functional Components), JavaScript (ES6+), SPAs, TypeScript, GatsbyJS, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Styled Components, Flexbox, CSS Frameworks (Bootstrap, Bulma, Material Design), Headless CMS (NetlifyCMS), Storybook, Git Version Control, Github, Gulp, NPM, Yarn, Webpack, Scrum/Agile, WCAG/AODA Accessibility, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Figma, Integrating REST APIs / JSON, UI / UX design, CI (Continuous Integration), Azure, AWS S3.

**Familiar with:** Redux, Node.js, Express, Vue, Angular, NextJS, Strapi, Unit Testing, Test Driven Development (TDD), Enzyme, Jest, Cypress, Mocha, CSS Grid, TailwindCSS, GraphQL, Contentful, Prismic, AWS.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Front-End Developer, Battlefield Equipment Rentals (Toromont Cat)

Dec 2019 - Present

- Developed features for web applications using React, TypeScript, CSS3, Sass, REST APIs, JSON, generating \$1,000,000 in new revenue in 1 month during the COVID-19 pandemic.
- Built a machine product calculator using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 & Sass boosting user engagement by 50%.
- Designed & developed homepage features using Adobe XD, JavaScript, REST APIs, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, Sass & Bootstrap increasing traffic by 200%.
- Designed & built internal website Toromont Cat NCE Machine Catalogue using React, JavaScript, React Context API helping sales staff when talking to customers.

## Front-End Developer (Contract), VelocityEHS

Jun 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Developed UI features, team lead for accessibility, mentored junior developers.
- Improved accessibility by 100% by using AODA AA accessible compliant JavaScript & HTML5.
- Reduced development time by 50% by integrating Storybook JavaScript & HTML5 code library.

## Front-End Developer & SEO, Freelance

Apr 2013 - Dec 2019

- Designed & developed Cass-A-Bella construction website using Adobe XD, React, JavaScript, GatsbyJS, CSS3, Sass & local SEO practices resulting in \$1,500,000 in new revenue.
- Built Infused Agency website using Adobe XD, React, JavaScript, GatsbyJS, Headless CMS, CSS3, Sass & local SEO practices increasing Google rankings from page 18 to page 1.
- Constructed KD Flowers website using Adobe XD, React, JavaSCript, GatsbyJS, CSS3, Sass with local SEO landing the website on page 1 of Google for multiple keywords, driving tens of thousands in new revenue.

## Front-End Developer, Thrillworks

Apr 2018 - Jun 2019

- Built responsive, AODA AA websites for multiple clients using HTML5, CSS3, Sass & JavaScript.
- Lessened development time by 60% through crafting reusable React / JavaScript code libraries.
- Fielded AODA AA Accessibility board, mentoring internal staff on accessibility.

## Front-End Developer, Virtual Image

Sep 2016 - Apr 2018

- Developed content management websites using HTML5, CSS3, Sass & JavaScript.
- Cut development time by 60% using HTML5, Sass, CSS3 & JavaScript code libraries.
- Enhanced client designs and increased user engagement by 50% compared to old websites.

Front-End Developer (Contract), Elite Digital Front-End Developer, iOPW

Mar 2016 - Sep 2016 Aug 2014 - Mar 2016

**SIDE PROJECTS** 

Designed & built Maple Leafs stats web application using React, React Hooks, Styled Components, JavaScript, Axios, REST API & Sass to fetch and display live season API data for the Leafs top 3 players.

**EDUCATION** 

**Durham College, Oshawa, ON** | Advanced Diploma in Multimedia Design

Sep 2007- Apr 2010